我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但是我在时间中迷失了
But I became lost in time.
我的朋友们用尽了一切办法才把我救回来
It took everything in my friends' power to bring me back,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
and in doing so our world was opened up to new threats.
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to stop them.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously, on the Flash.
我不是鬼魂  我是莱奥·史纳特  来自地球X
I'm not a ghost. I'm Leo Snart, from Earth-X.
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything!
我明白  但你的放射性很危险
I understand, but your radioactivity is dangerous.
你是团队的一员
You are part of this team.
而且我是唯一一个迪沃
And I'm the only one with a body
想要夺取身体的人
that DeVoe is trying to snatch.
你要为我而死
Now you will die, for me.
融化
Melt.
-冰霜杀手  -消失了
- Killer Frost... - Is gone.
我的新宿体有个附加的好处
My new host body holds an ancillary benefit.
暗物质  从威尔斯博士给他那顶山寨帽子
Dark matter, siphoned from the room
充能的房间里吸取到的
where Dr. Wells was charging his counterfeit cap.
马上注入最大剂量
Maximum capacity, now!
再来一次
Again.
威尔斯博士  出现不同结果的概率
Dr. Wells, the odds of a different conclusion
-很低  -再运算一次
- are extremely low. - Run it again.
是  威尔斯博士
Yes, Dr. Wells.
相同结果  威尔斯博士
Same results, Dr. Wells.
注入你神经系统的
The excessive infusion of dark matter
过量暗物质已经破坏了
into your neural system has disrupted the area
主管智力和决策的区域
of the brain where general intelligence and executive function occur.
我吸收新信息的能力正在衰退
My ability to integrate new information is declining.
我正在失去我的智力
I'm losing my intelligence.
很快你就需要重新学习
At some point soon you need to relearn
你所知道的一切
everything you've ever known.
可以用思考帽
Is there a way to use the thinking cap
逆转这个进程吗
to reverse this process?
不太可能  威尔斯博士
Unlikely, Dr. Wells.
你的思考帽和暗物质正是造成这个的罪魁祸首
Your thinking cap and the dark matter is what caused this.
我曾试图控制剂量
I tried to caution restraint--
我知道
I know!
吉迪恩  还有多久我会忘记
Gideon, how long before everything I know...
一切
is gone?
闪 电 侠
第四季
第十九集
他去世到现在只有几天  但
You know, it's only been a couple days since he died, but...
仍然感觉不真实
it still doesn't feel real.
你们和拉尔夫有多亲近
How close were you with Ralph?
我们正在变得亲近
We were becoming close.
我们刚认识时我花了点功夫
Yeah, it took me a while to see past the things
才看到我不喜欢的东西之外的事情
that I didn't like when we first met,
但很快
but after a while,
我看到他是个多么好的人
I started to see what a good guy he was.
看到他成为一个英雄
Started to see the hero that he became.
你认为他是个英雄
You consider him a hero?
对  我这么认为
Yeah. Yeah I do.
你呢  巴里
What about you, Barry?
-你感觉如何  -我没事
- How are you feeling? - I'm fine.
我在努力接受这个
I mean, you know, i'm working through it.
所以你和他没有爱瑞丝和他亲近
So you weren't as close to him as Iris was?
不  我们差不多
No, I mean, we were about the same, I'd say.
他们之前一起工作
They used to work together.
-是吗  -对
- Oh? - Yeah.
但你现在对他的死
And you're fine already?
已经坦然接受了吗
with his death?
我这辈子见多了死亡
I've dealt with a lot of death in my life.
你是见多了
Yes, you have.
你的母亲  父亲  艾迪  罗尼  HR
Your mother, father, Eddie, Ronnie, H.R..
拉尔夫的死对你到底有影响吗
Has Ralph's death had any impact on you at all?
我就是学会如何面对死亡了
I think I just know how to deal with death now,
所以对我的打击不像以前那么大
so it doesn't affect me as much as it once did.
我们晚点再继续吧
All right, i guess we'll pick this up later.
对
Yeah.
下周同一时间
Same time next week?
要是你们需要的话早点也可以
Or before if you need.
巴里  悲痛是一种复杂的
Barry... grief is a complex emotion
有着自己的特性的情感
that, as you know, deals on its own terms.
不存在熟能生巧这回事
There is no practice makes perfect.
渴吗  我的爱人
Thirsty, my love?
[外语]
你很高兴
You're happy.
很久都没这么高兴了  我的爱人
More than I've been in a long time, my love.
致你的归来
To your return.
我从未离开你  马尔利泽
I never left you, Marlize.
感觉像是你离开过
It felt like you had.
那些日子过去了
Those days are past us now.
我们所有的牺牲  我们的承诺
All our sacrifice, our commitment,
我们的计划  一切都顺利进行
our planning, everything is as it was.
甚至更好
and more.
生理扫描
自从你上次转移后
There's been no decline in your metabolic processes
你的新陈代谢功能没有衰退过
since your last transference.
我的大脑  我的能力
My mind, my abilities--
这些弹性细胞
these elasticized cells
可以容纳另外一整车超能力者的能力
can hold another bus full of meta-human powers
并让我不受影响
and I still wouldn't be affected.
这让我安心  克利福德
That gives me peace, Clifford.
我要你专注于接下来的事情
I need your mind focused for what happens next.
-我们今天就开始  -对
- We start today? - Yes.
但我们有时间  我的爱人
But we have time, my love.
我们不能享有一点儿二人世界
Could we not spend time together
作为夫妻  我想
as husband and wife? I think--
这是你犯的第一个错误
Mm, that is-- that is your first mistake.
把需要思考的事留给我
Leave the thinking to me.
停  别管它
Whoa! Stop, don't bother.
它不起作用的
It doesn't work.
-我不知道  -我知道
- I don't know about that. - Yeah, well I know about it.
我是那个戴这玩意的人
I'm guy who wore it on his head.
它帮你对付了迪沃  对吗
And it helped you gain ground on DeVoe, didn't it?
定位口袋维度  制作权杖
Mapping the pocket dimensions, building the Scepter.
就在我们最需要它时
We stopped you from using it
我们拦着你用它  结果拉尔夫被
right when we needed it most, when Ralph got...
我们以为你上瘾了
We thought you were addicted.
我们不应该阻止你的
We shouldn't have stopped you.
我们错了
We were wrong.
实际上  不  你们没错
Actually, no--you know what, you weren't wrong.
没错  我确实上瘾了
No, I was-- I was addicted.
想想很蠢
Yeah, which is stupid when you think about it.
因为我已经很聪明了
Because I'm a pretty smart guy.
这个智力增强器能让我再聪明多少呢
How much smarter was this Intelligence Booster making me?
百分之十
10%?
我认为我们都同意迪沃的聪明度
I think we both agree that DeVoe is at least
至少比那高出两倍
twice as smart as that.
那也许我也该戴上它吧
Then maybe I should get to wear it too.
不行
Okay, no.
不行  这东西在你脑袋上根本没用
No, this thing would never work on you,
因为这是我特别设计
because I specifically designed this
来刺激我的脑波的
to stimulate my brain waves.
是我的脑波  不是你的
My brain waves, not yours, okay?
我大脑丰富的想像力
My cerebral firings, 'kay?
哈里  哈里  我是在说我们应该
Harry, Harry, I'm saying we should build
做第二个思考帽
a second thinking cap.
-智力增强器吗  -为我做一个
- Intelligence Booster? - For me.
为你
For-for you?
是的  为我  你想想看
Yes, for me. Think about it.
两个大脑肯定强大过一个大脑
Two heads are better than one.
你的想法和我的想法
Your ideas, my ideas.
加在一起  我们把想法结合在一起
Put 'em together. We combine them.
以彼此的想法为基础
We build upon each other's ideas.
哈里  有了两个帽子
Harry, with two caps...
有了两个帽子  我们就能打败迪沃
With two caps we could get DeVoe.
好  那开始做吧
Okay. Get on it.
融化
Melt.
-有什么好消息吗  -没有迪沃的踪影
- Anything new? - No sign of DeVoe.
我是说你
I meant with you.
没有
No.
市里没发现有冷能的踪迹
No cold signatures anywhere in the city.
完全找不到冰霜杀手
Killer Frost is nowhere to be found.
这不对啊
That doesn't make sense;
迪沃把车上的人都变成超能力者肯定有原因的
I mean, DeVoe created every bus meta for a reason.
他对巴里或西斯科的超能力都没兴趣
I mean, he had no interest in Barry's powers
包括铁山监狱的超能力者
or Cisco's, or any of the metas in Iron Heights,
所以我不知道他为什么突然间想要你的超能力
so I don't know why he would suddenly want yours.
我们都看到了所发生的事
We all saw what happened.
当迪沃碰到我的时候  我的超能力就消失了
When DeVoe touched me, my powers disappeared.
肯定是因为他
Had to be him.
是迪沃吗
DeVoe?
卫星收到了三个不同的口袋维度
Uh, satellite's picking up three different pocket dimensions
正在楔石城打开
opening in Keystone.
我们每个人...
Let's each--
你和我  雷  我们走
All right, you and me, Ray, let's go.
别急  等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
维度刚刚全关上了
They all just closed.
什么
What?
搞错坐标了吗  也许他只是弄错了
Huh. Wrong coordinates? Maybe... maybe he made a mistake.
他不会弄错的
He doesn't make mistakes.
他在楔石城肯定有所图谋
He must want something in Keystone.
水星实验室
-特蕾西·布兰德的实验室  -他在找辐射
- Tracy Brand's lab. - He's going after fallout.
打给特蕾西
All right, call Tracy.
告诉她我们去找博尔曼
Tell her we're coming for Borman, okay?
等等  然后呢
Wait, and gonna do what?
带他去别的地方
Just to take him somewhere else.
我们不能带他来这里
Well, we can't take him here.
我们甚至没法牵制他的放射性尘埃
We can't even contain his fallout.
特蕾西也只能勉强牵制他的超能力
Tracy's barely been able to contain his powers as is.
这家伙就像是一颗待炸的核炸弹
Yeah, the guy's a nuclear explosion waiting to go off.
我不知道你
And I don't know about you,
但是我今年的核炸弹已经爆过了
but I-- I've had my fill of nuclear bombs this year.
但如果我们能让他冷静下来
But if we can cool him down,
我们就能带他去一个安全的地方
we can get him somewhere safe.
那史纳特的冷冻枪呢
What about Snart's cold gun?
我有枪的原型
I mean, I have a prototype,
但要改良至我们的需求才行
but to modify it to our needs,
那至少需要一天的时间
that would take at least a day.
我们没有这么多时间
We don't have that kind of time.
迪沃要去找他
DeVoe's coming for him.
迪沃已经掌握了我们的每一步行动
DeVoe has known our every move.
我是说我们得做一些他预料不到的事
I mean, we've gotta do something that he hasn't accounted for.
我们要怎么想出办法让博尔曼冷静下来
How are we supposed to find a way to cool down Borman
然后想一个迪沃预料不到的计划
and take him somewhere DeVoe won't know about
带他去一个迪沃不知道的地方呢
with a plan he won't see coming?
打给莱拉
Call Lyla.
看看天眼会是否有隔离外界的东西
See if A.R.G.U.S. has anything off the grid.
但就算他们有  我们要怎么解决
Okay, but even if they do, I mean, what are we going to do
另外两个问题
about the other two problems?
地球X
战争结束了
War's over!
坏小子赢了  姑娘们输了
Bad guys and girls lost.
纳粹政权已经瓦解
Nazi regime's been dismantled.
现在由反抗军掌权了
And the rebellion's in charge now.
你何不自己站出来呢
Why don't you turn yourself in?
这样我们就不必继续猫捉老鼠了
Save us the Tom and Jerry.
把怒火发泄在其他被误导的事上
Find some other misguided cause to get all aggro about.
不能对这位骑士这样
Not this knight.
我会一直战斗  直至你们每一个人
I will fight until every last one of you
获得和我的兄弟姐妹同样的命运
finds the same fate as my brothers and sisters.
你们来得正是时候
Your timing is impeccable.
我们的地球需要你帮忙
We need your help on our Earth.
现在吗  我有点忙
Right now? I'm kinda busy.
忙什么  忙着死吗
Doing what? Dying?
说得好
Touche!
你们要阻止一个
So, you're trying to stop a guy
认为自己比任何人都聪明的人
who thinks he's smarter than everyone
而他的那个信徒爱人
and his true-believer lover,
不择手段  不惜一切代价也要实现其邪恶阴谋
who are hell-bent on achieving their evil machinations at any cost.
正合我意
Well, it's right up my alley.
但是迪沃真的比所有的人都要聪明
Except DeVoe actually is smarter than everyone.
他创造了12个超能力者
He created 12 meta-humans
好让他窃取其超能力
just so he could steal their powers.
但是在这个过程中  他让他们全死了
And he left everybody dead in the process.
包括拉尔夫·德比  他曾经是我们的一员
Including Ralph Dibny, who was a team member of ours.
对不起  这肯定很难过
I'm sorry. That's rough.
这些人的死都令人难过
All these deaths have been rough.
我们现在不能想这件事
We can't dwell on it right now.
我们得专心应对
You know, we have to focus
这样迪沃就不知道我们的行动
so DeVoe doesn't know what we're doing
我们就有机会救博尔曼
and we have a shot at saving Borman.
所以我们才来找你
Which is why we came to you.
原来只是因为我是个局外人
Oh, I see, and I'm just outside the box enough
能对迪沃出其不意
to catch DeVoe off-guard.
没错  而且我们需要你的冷冻枪
That, and we need your cold gun.
用来做什么
Oh? For what?
我们一直在尽力改良辐射防护服
We've been working on modifying a radiation hazmat suit
用来调节他体内的温度
to regulate his internal temperature
在转移他的时候  阻止他的心脏
to keep his core from raising to the point of detonation
上升到达引爆点
during transport.
你的冷冻枪会是我们的应急措施
Your cold gun would be our backup.
现在肯定是欢乐时光  我算是买一赠一了
It must be happy hour, and I'm the two-for-one.
你那位冰霜朋友呢
What about your chilly friend?
她不想一起来玩玩吗
She doesn't want in on the fun?
-她走了  -真可惜
- She's gone. - That's too bad.
我给你们24小时的时间
All right, you get me for 24 hours.
-多一分钟都不行  -等等  为什么
- Not a minute more. - Wait, why not?
因为我想让雷做一个遵守承诺的人
Because I thought I'd make Ray an honest man.
就在明天
Tomorrow.
-你要结婚吗  -太兴奋了
- You're getting married? - That's so exciting!
我觉得要是你俩能成
I figured if you two could make it,
-那我们也能  -什么
- so could we. - What?
-不  是我们  -我开玩笑的
- No, we- - I tease.
那么  咱们要把这人送到哪去
So, where are we moving this guy to?
天眼会在新布莱顿有个设施
A.R.G.U.S. has a facility in New Brighton.
高科技  高安保  他在那里应该很安全
High tech, high security-he should be safe there.
战衣还有多久能好
And how long till you're done with the suit?
还剩几个地方
Few more tweaks.
好  我去告诉我爸计划详情
Okay. I'm gonna go call my dad and let him know the plan.
这就是了吗  你搞完了
Is that it? Are you done?
好吧  说实话
Yeah, well, the truth is,
第一顶比较难做出来
the first one was the hard part.
这个比较简单  基本就是跟着设计...
This one is simply, basically following the plan's...
没错  咱们来试验一下吧
Precisely! Let's take this for a spin, shall we?
好了  开始吧
Oh, all right, go ahead.
来吧  坐下
Here. Have a seat.
好了
Okay.
好吧  我想...
All right, then I guess...
我相信你
I trust you.
这个我知道
No, I know that.
好了  开始了
Okay, here we go.
-连接上了  -有点痒
- Connection established. - Hmm, tingles.
是的
Yeah.
感觉有点像我的空调
Kinda feels like my conditioner!
这是你突触体活跃增强
That's your synaptic activity enhancing.
天  真够可以
Boy, is it ever.
我脑子里跟开派对似的
It's like a party in my brain.
我理解你为什么这么喜欢这玩意了
I can see why you like this thing so much.
我都能感觉到神经元在燃烧
I can feel my neurons firing.
好吧
Okay!
皮卡丘
Pikachu!
哈里
Harry!
-哈里  -好了  好好好
- Harry! - Yeah, yeah, yup, yup, yup.
你知道吗  我觉得
Yeah, you know what, I think
这个样子大概是因为超限额阈值  那个
what happened, probably a hyper-limiter valve, that, uh--
叵离子二极管
Promethium ion diodes.
-叵离子二极管  对  -让帽子过载了
- Promethium ion diode, yep. - They overloaded the cap.
-过载了  真倒霉  -最起码我们试过了
- Overloaded. Real bummer. - Oh, well. We tried.
你是怎么搞到叵离子二极管的
How the hell'd you get promethium ion diodes?
我是从  从我实验室里
Oh, I got 'em. I--in my lab
在我地球上  那里有  但已经没有了
on my Earth, had 'em there, but I'm all out, unfortunately.
我们这里没有
We don't have any here.
要搞到可要好几周
It would take us weeks to get some.
那这个就这样吧
Oh, well. Well, you know what,
咱们先延期欠着
we'll put in a back order.
我看看能不能想出点别的
I'll see if I can come up with something else.
好吧
Right.
看起来我们的恐吓战术成功了
I see our scare tactics worked.
他们会按照你的预估移动那东西
They're going to move the asset as you anticipated.
是  但不幸的是与我预测的地点不同
Yes, but unfortunately not to a location I predicted.
这是什么
What is this?
你最喜欢的衣服
Your favorite dress.
你现在突然想穿了吗
And you chose to wear that now?
为了讨好你啊  亲爱的
To please you, my love.
能讨好我的是你能理解
What would please me is your understanding
我们现在事业的重要性
of the gravity of our undertaking.
纠正被误导的人类进程
To right the misguided course of all humanity.
我只是想...
I just thought
你看  又是你的想法
You see, again, you thought.
引领你到了这琐碎的情感中
Which led you to this trivial emotion.
现在去换点更合适的衣服
Now, change into something a bit more appropriate.
你的角色  从现在到大悟之道开始
Your role, from now until the enlightenment has occurred,
就是遵从我的安排
is as my technician.
现在让我一个人好好思考下
Now leave me be so that I can figure out
如何引导闪电侠小队
a way to motivate Team Flash
将我们的猎物送到原本预期的地点
to deliver our quarry to where initially intended.
好吧  我想咱们应该上14号大道
All right, look, I think we take Highway 14.
没有比这个更乡下的了
It's as rural as we're going to get.
而且是直接通向新布莱顿
It's a straight shot to New Brighten.
最能保证辐射的安全
Best chance to get Fallout to safety.
听起来计划不错  巴里
Sounds like a plan, Barry.
你知道我对做计划是什么感觉
You know how I feel about plans.
是
Yep.
这是你们的一员吗
This was your team member, right?
拉尔夫·德比
Ralph Dibny?
是的  伸缩人
Yeah, Elongated Man.
伸缩人
Elongated Man
不记得有叫这个名字的人
Don't remember someone with that name
与我们一同打过纳粹
being a part of the fight against the Nazis.
没有  他  他当时没准备好
No, no, he, um... he wasn't ready yet.
一个菜鸟英雄
Ah, a rookie hero.
你训练他了吗
So you trained him?
尽我一切努力  训练了
As much as I could, yeah.
一个亲手训练之人的死更让人难以接受
Even harder death to take, someone you've mentored.
但你看起来很平静  尤其是这件事
And yet somehow you seem okay, considering this happened,
发生了才过几天
what, just a few days ago?
我没事  我只是
I am okay. I'm just...
想着做有必要的事情
trying to do what I have to do.
我想要专注在任务上
I'm trying to stay on task.
是吗  你是在做这种事啊
Oh, is that what you're doing?
你知道在我们对抗纳粹混蛋的这些年里
Do you know how many rebels we lost over the years, Barry,
失去了多少反抗军吗  巴里
trying to defeat those Nazi bastards?
-肯定是无数的  -不是无数
- Countless, I'm sure. - Not countless.
有数
Counted.
18,322.
3679位在我领导下死亡
3,679 were under my watch.
我感觉得到他们每个人死亡时的重量
And I felt the weight of each of their deaths.
在他们死后多年我仍能感受到
I still do, some years after they die.
-好吧  你看...  -我察觉到
- Yeah, look- - The thing I realized
要想继续领导  保持清醒
is that to continue to lead, to be clear-headed,
我必须默哀那些失去的男男女女
I had to grieve for those men and women I lost.
所以我就这么做了  为每一个人
So I did. Each and every one.
你看  巴里
Look, Barry.
你想让我帮助你移动一个超能人体核弹
You want me to help you move a meta-human nuclear bomb
躲过某个有着这板上所有超能力的天才
that some genius with nearly every meta-power on this board
我会尽我所能
is after, I will do what I can,
只要你能够有颗清醒的头脑
as long as your head is on straight.
因为如果我在和雷结婚前死了
Because if I die before Ray and I get married,
雷会杀了我
Ray will kill me.
战衣准备好了
Suits ready.
辐射也在特蕾西的实验室做好准备了
And Fallout is ready at Tracy's lab.
咱们去楔石城吧
So let's get to Keystone.
-你还好吧  -我很好
- You good? - I'm good.
那就让咱们去接那家伙吧
Then let's go get our guy.
超能人体核弹
Meta-human nuclear bomb...
核弹
Nuclear bomb...
辐射也在特蕾西的实验室做好准备了
And Fallout is ready at Tracy's lab...
Fallout is ready at Tracy's lab...
咱们去楔石城吧
Let's get to Keystone...
那就让咱们去接那家伙吧
Let's go get our guy...
没错  去吧
Yes, let's.
毕竟  核弹浪费了可不好
After all, a nuke is a terrible thing to waste.
你是说我得一直穿着这玩意吗
You're telling me I have to wear this thing the whole time?
听着  这衣服能保护我们免受你的辐射
Yeah, look, that suit protects us from you
这样我们就可以保护你
so that we can protect you from the guy
不被那个人抓到
that's trying to hunt you down.
他为什么要抓我
Why is he after me?
说实话  尼尔  我们不知道  但我们
Honestly, Neil, we don't know, but we want to find out
和你一样想找出原因
as much as you do.
而且我们会的  相信我
And we will. Trust me.
你救过我一次  闪电侠
Saved me once, Flash,
相信你会再救我一次的
I trust you to do it again.
那是什么
What's that?
我做的鸡尾酒
I whipped up this cocktail
里面有雾化的二乙基三胺五乙酸和碘化钾
of atomized DTPA and potassium iodide.
会让我们的甲状腺充满
It should flood our thyroids
足够的非放射性碘
with enough non-radioactive iodine
如果我们的制服失效了
so that if our containment suit doesn't work,
它能给我们提供一些防辐射保护
it should offer us some protection from radiation.
一些保护  真是敷衍的安慰
Some protection, how vaguely reassuring.
-能持续多久  -两小时  最多三小时
- How long will this last? - Two, three hours max.
你们最好开始行动了
You'd better get going.
好  我们再重复一遍计划  好吗
All right. Let's just go over the plan one more time, okay?
我会在货车前面跑
I'm going to be running ahead of the truck,
侦查路上有没有出问题的迹象
scouting the route for any signs of trouble.
我会在尖端科研实验室
Right, I will be at S.T.A.R. Labs
追踪路上的任何口袋维度
tracking any pocket dimension en route.
我和尼尔一起在货车里
And I'll be in the truck with Neil
监控他的生命体征和辐射指数
monitoring his vitals and rads.
我会准备好
With me at the ready,
以防我们的超破坏性超能力者造成蘑菇云
in case our meta of mass destruction here goes all mushroom cloud.
-无意冒犯  -我来开车
- No offense. - And I'll be driving.
同时背诵塞西尔教给我的所有祷告
And reciting every prayer that Cecile's ever taught me.
我可能会和你一起祈祷
I might join you.
各位  我知道迪沃给我们带来了沉重打击
Look, guys, I know DeVoe's hit us pretty hard,
但是现在我们
but right now let's just--
先忘掉他从我们这里夺走了什么
let's try to forget what he's taken from us,
集中精力去夺取他的东西
and stay focused on taking something from him
把尼尔安全送到天眼会
by getting Neil safely to A.R.G.U.S.
我们做到这一点  迪沃的计划就失败了
We do that, whatever DeVoe has planned falls apart.
赢得这场战斗有望帮助我们赢得整场战争
Winning this battle may just win us this war.
说得真好
Hear, hear!
我们在这场游戏中保持专注
Let's all make sure we keep our heads in the game.
就能保证自己的安全
So we can stay safe out there.
我知道这意味着什么
I know what that was about.
演讲很不错  巴里
It was a good speech, Barry.
想确保你也听到了  而不只是说给别人听
Just making sure you heard it, didn't just give it.
这话是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
要是你不能控制好自己的感情
If you don't confront your feelings,
它们就会控制你
they will confront you.
我这里什么都没看到
All clear on my end.
这一地区没有口袋维度活动
There's no pocket dimension activity in the area.
道路也没有问题  乔
Roads are looking good too. Joe?
装备安全
Yeah, the rig is secure.
-凯特琳  -辐射指数良好
- Caitlyn? - Rads are good.
心跳正常
Heartbeat regular.
在地球X  我们有一句谚语
On Earth-X, we have a saying.
如果你笑出声的话  就得分享这个笑话
If you laugh out loud, you got to share the joke.
这是生活在一个
Byproduct of living on an Earth
缺少乐趣的地球上的副产品
where joy is a scarce commodity.
这是冰霜杀手留下的便利贴
It's a post-it note from Killer Frost.
我们这样交流  曾经这样
It's how we talk. Talked.
又把温控器弄坏了  我想它恨我
Broke the thermostat again. I think it hates me.
真可爱
It's cute.
你想她吗
Do you miss her?
并不是  只是
It's not that... it's just that...
我们刚刚开始变得亲密起来
we were starting to become close lately.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
And I know how crazy that sounds
鉴于我们在谈论的这个人
considering we're talking about someone
事实上活在我的身体里
who actually lived inside of me.
我正在外地球运输人体炸弹
I'm on an alt-Earth transporting a human bomb
和一支可以去到未来的护卫队一起
with an escort that can literally run back to the future.
你的故事是我这一天听到的最不疯狂的事了
Your story is the least crazy thing I've heard all day.
有一件事可以确定
One thing's for sure.
我会想念这些小纸条的
I will miss those little notes.
不管她是不是另一个你
Alter-ego or not,
怀念我们失去的人是很正常的
it's okay to miss someone we've lost.
他怎么样
How's he doing?
很好  他的辐射指数很低
Good. His rads are low,
生命体征平稳
vitals seem stable.
我给他打了镇定剂  看起来起效了
I gave him a sedative, and it seems to be working.
好  我们快到了
Okay, good, we're almost there--
各位  发现口袋维度活动
Guys, there's pocket dimension activity.
乔
-爸爸  -我被困住了
- Dad! - I'm trapped in here.
门没有锁  但是
The door's unlocked, but--
但是很重
but it's just like-- it weighs a ton.
爱瑞丝
Iris?
-爱瑞丝  -爸爸
- Iris? - Dad?
通讯器坏了  是迪沃
The comms are out. It's DeVoe.
他在这里吗
He's here?
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen.
像往常一样  你比我晚了一步
As usual, you're a step behind me.
这是双关语
Yay, puns.
你们地球一的反派真有趣
You Earth-1 villains sure are a hoot.
超乎你的想像  史纳特先生
You have no idea, Mr. Snart.
你没去抓辐射
You're not taking Fallout.
我能  而且我会的  不是现在在这里
I can, and I will, if not here and now,
就是等你把他绝密转移到天眼会之后
then after your top-secret transfer to A.R.G.U.S.
我知道
Yes, I know.
记得吗
Remember?
很好  我不用为这样做感到愧疚了
Good, I won't have to feel guilty about doing this.
这招真厉害
Well, that de-escalated quickly.
你这个小玩具
The miniscule sound waves
发出的微小声波
produced by that toy trinket of yours
对我这具新宿体来说太弱了
are far too weak for this new body of mine.
德比先生的礼物真好
What a gift Mr. Dibny provided.
在某种意义上来说这的确是个礼物
Well, it was a gift in a manner of speaking.
不是吗  菜鸟
Right, rookie?
巴里
Barry.
你的思维为什么如此混乱  艾伦先生
Why such turmoil in your mind, Mr. Allen?
让我来减轻你的痛苦
Allow me to ease your pain.
够了  我要走了
That's it! I'm leaving!
不行  你得呆在这
No, no, no, I need you to stay here
保持冷静  尼尔  等等
and calm down. Neil, wait!
我要你们每个人认真听我讲话
I want you all to listen to me very carefully,
希望我不需要提高音量
and hopefully I won't have to raise my voice.
这辆卡车现在归我了
This truck is now mine.
我们真的没法找到乔和凯特琳吗
We really have no way of finding Joe and Caitlyn?
追踪辐射也不行吗
Not even by tracking Fallout?
那套防护服屏蔽了他的辐射指数
That hazmat suit is hiding his radiation signature.
所以卫星定位不到他
So the satellite can't even find him
除非他变热
unless he heats up.
关于劳蕾尔·兰斯的二重身
Okay, well, what do you know about
你都知道些什么
Laurel Lance's doppelganger?
她为什么追你
And why was she hunting you?
那是海妖X
That was Siren-X,
德意志军团的残余力量
all that's left of the Reichsmen.
一个失去理智的的精英杀手
An elite assassin gone mad,
而且她很残忍
and she is relentless.
暗恋着黑箭  不求回报的
Carried a torch for Dark Arrow, unrequited,
所以她对于对他的死负有责任的人
so she's none too pleased with those responsible
都不太友好  包括现在的公司
for his death, present company included.
所以她的超能力和黑海妖一样吗
So she has the same powers as Black Siren?
地球2的劳蕾尔·兰斯
The Laurel Lance of Earth-2.
那地球1的劳蕾尔·兰斯
And Earth-1's Laurel Lance...
她死了
She died.
她是她姐姐之后的第二位黑金丝雀
She was the second Black Canary after her sister,
那位也是死了之后回来了
who also died and came back,
但名字是白金丝雀  因为...
but as White Canary, cause--
-西斯科  -这很复杂
- Cisco. - It's complicated.
对  二重身的疑惑先放一放
Right. Doppelganger confusion aside,
海妖X现在有我的冷冻枪和核武器
Siren-X has my cold-gun and a nuke,
而且现在她复仇的渴望无法阻止她
and her thirst for vengeance won't prevent her
用其中任何一样对付我或你们
from using either one on me or all of you now.
你确定自己还好吗
Hey, are you sure you're okay?
-我没事  -我只是有些担心
- I'm fine. - I'm just a little worried.
看上去当时她抢先了一步
It seemed like she got the jump on you out there.
不是  只是我当时没防备
She didn't. She just caught me off-guard.
而且现在这有什么重要
And why does it matter right now?
我们都不知道乔和凯特琳在哪里
We don't even know where Joe and Caitlyn are.
-我... -西斯科  你能不能
- I--  - Cisco, will you just
-看看哈里有主意没  -我去问
- see if Harry has any ideas? - I'm on it.
保持警觉盯着卫星
Just watch the satellites like a hawk.
莱昂  当时到底发生什么了
Leo, what exactly happened out there?
只是典型的两个来自不同地球的
Oh, just your typical deadly combat
超能力者之间的殊死搏斗
between two metas from multiple earths.
莱昂纳多
Leonard.
-我去和他谈谈  -谢谢
- I'll go talk to him. - Thank you.
它在哪
Where is it?
拉蒙  你在干什么
Hey, Ramon, wh--what are you doing?
一个纳粹版的劳蕾尔·兰斯绑架了凯特琳和乔
A Nazi Laurel Lance just kidnapped Caitlyn and Joe.
得让这玩意儿派上用场
We're going to make this thing work,
我们现在就要用上它
and we're going to make it work now.
不行  我们办不到
Okay, well, we can't. We can't,
我还没有找到一个可以替代它...
I still haven't found a replacement for that--
你在哪里弄到的
where did you get that?
在吉普赛给我的一个魔方里找到的
I found this in one of the cubes Gypsy sent me.
真聪明  你知道吗  拉蒙
How clever of you. You know what, Ramon?
这还是没用的
It's still not going to work. It's not gonna work.
-为什么  -因为就是没用
- Why? - Because it's not gonna work.
好吗  因为这是浪费时间
Okay? Because it's a waste of time.
因为我说了  这就是原因
Because I said so! That's why!
-那样的话  -拉蒙
- Well, in that case-- - Listen, Ramon--
我们的朋友命悬一线
Our friends' lives are at stake.
-你不能...  -听好
- You don't-- - Look!
我不知道你怎么了
I don't know what's going on with you,
如果你不帮我  我...
but if you're not going to help me with this thing, I--
我去
What--
为什么这么做
Why would you do that?
为了保护你
To protect you.
这是帽子干的吗
The cap did this?
还有暗物质
And dark matter.
你用了暗物质
You used dark matter?
我用了暗物质  拉蒙
I used dark matter. It--look, Ramon.
这是唯一的选择
It was the only way.
唯一的什么选择
The only way to do what?
烧掉你的神经元吗
Fry your synapses?
哈里  你跟我保证过
Harry, you promised me.
我知道我保证过
I know I promised you, I promised you.
天呐
Oh, my god.
哈里  你怎么能这么傻
Harry, how could you be so stupid?
-因为我觉得自己傻  -我们现在都觉得自己很傻
- 'Cause I felt so stupid! - We all feel stupid right now!
是  但你是震波  艾伦是闪电侠
Yes, but you're Vibe, Allen's the Flash.
我是什么
Who am I?
我唯一能做的
My only job
就是聪明过
is to be smarter
所有想要伤害小队成员的坏人
than all the villains who want to hurt this team,
这都做不到  我就是废物
and without that, I'm nothing.
我就要失去对于这个小队而言
I'm about to lose the only part of me
自己唯一的价值了
that has any value to this team,
我唯一有点用处的地方了
the only part of me that matters.
所以是的  我毁了帽子
And so, yeah, I destroyed the cap.
为了你不要犯跟我同样的错误
So that you wouldn't make the same mistake I did.
不该这样的
This should not be happening.
也许你计算错误
Perhaps you miscalculated.
一切我都计算在握
I calculated everything.
闪电侠参与了巴士超能力者的过程
The Flash's involvement with the bus meta,
史纳特的二重身的回归
the recruitment of Snart's doppelganger,
甚至地球X的女妖的到来
even the arrival of the Earth-X banshee.
每件事的发生和我预期的一摸一样
Every event occurred exactly as I predicted.
除了结果
Except the outcome!
你应该打败海妖X吗
You were supposed to defeat Siren-X?
不是
No.
闪电侠应该击败她  但...
The Flash was, but...
巴里·艾伦就站在那里  一动不动
Barry Allen just stood there, frozen.
现在我失去了唯一的核能超能力者
And now I've lost my only nuclear meta
就因为闪电侠失败了
because The Flash failed!
他为什么会失败
Why? Why did he fail?
也许有我们没考虑到的变量
Perhaps there were variables that we just did not consider.
我已经解释过了  没有任何变量
As I already explained, there is no variable
超出了我的计算
beyond my examination.
即使没那么明显
Even less apparent.
上次巴里·艾伦见到你
The last time Barry Allen saw you,
你夺去了他挚友的生命
you took the life of his close friend,
现在他看到你  愣住了
and now he sees you and he pauses.
你真没看到吗
You really don't see it?
你能计算出多个地球间
You can calculate near-infinite outcomes
近无限多的结果  但却不能算出
across multiple Earths, but you cannot account
别人的感受
for how someone is feeling.
雷达扫描
你当时看到了什么  巴里
What'd you see out there, Barry?
愣在那里的时候
When you froze up?
什么都没看到
Nothing.
当时你让两个队友被俘
You just got two of your teammates captured
还差点害我送命
and almost got me killed.
所以你不解释下原因我不会走的
So either you explain what happened or I leave.
-我看到拉尔夫了  -我警告过你
- I saw Ralph. - Mm, I warned you.
他会扰乱你的大脑
He is messing with your head.
不是那样
No, it's not like that.
我想他吗  是的
Do I miss him? Yes.
我对当时的事后悔吗  当然
Do I regret what happened? Of course.
但我不需要在失去中汲取教训
But I don't need lessons in loss.
我现在要做的是领导好队伍
What I need to do right now is lead my team.
如果你处理不好这事
Well, you're gonna lead them to their deaths
你就会把他们领导向坟墓
if you don't deal with this.
走开  莱昂
Back off, Leo.
你得默哀他  巴里
You need to grieve him, Barry.
默哀太奢侈了  我没时间
Grief is a luxury I don't have time for.
-挤出时间  -我不能
- Make time! - I can't!
不能是
Not...
拉尔夫  不能是现在
Ralph, not right now.
所以我们终于接近核心了
So we've finally reached the core.
你不想面对这种伤痛
You don't want to grieve this wound.
所以拉尔夫的死一定和你曾经
So Ralph's death must be different
经历过的失去不同  但为什么呢
from all the other losses you've experienced, but why?
为什么
Why?
巴里  相信我
Barry, trust me.
跑得再快也躲不开悲伤
There is no outrunning grief.
我不是有意讽刺你  抱歉
If that was a pun, I'm sorry.
跑  快跑
Run, run!
中城警局  勇敢者的家园
CCPD, home of the brave
死亡的大地
land of the dead.
把这些人都杀死
Killing all these people
你的朝代也回不来了
won't bring back your regime.
确实不能
No, it won't.
但屠杀你们这些所谓的警员
But decimating your so-called officers
能让这里更接近我的目标
will make it a hell of a lot more even.
我会保证的
I'll make sure of it.
-摘下头盔  -什么
- Remove your helmet. - What?
快摘下来
Take it off!
位置  中城警局
中城警局  她为什么要带他来这儿
CCPD. Why would she take him there?
我们毁了她的保护者
We destroyed her protectors.
也许她想以其人之道还治其人之身
Maybe she wants to do the same to us.
哈里  我们需要看监控
Harry, we need eyes.
要不你就交给我处理吧  好吗
You know what? Why don't you let me take care of it, all right?
你看好拉德计量
You keep an eye on the RADS.
莱昂  到我们了
Leo, we're on.
巴里  我从不懈怠的
Barry, I'm always on.
-等等  我需要...  -给你备好了
- Oh wait, I need a-- - Oh, got you.
谢谢你  爱瑞丝
Thank you, Iris.
注射还剩下多少时间
How much time do we have left on the injection?
不够多了
Not enough.
巴里
Barry!
这一下报你毁了我的世界之仇
This is for destroying my world!
-7000拉德  -还在上升
- 7,000 RADS. - And climbing.
7008拉德
各位  你们必须给他降温
Guys, you gotta cool him down.
8000拉德  还在上升
8,000 RADS and climbing.
辐射信号  8021拉德
闪电侠  站起来  站起来
Flash, get up. Get up!
闪电侠  人们就要死了  闪电侠
Flash, people are going to die, Flash.
我还没准备好去死呢
I'm not ready to die.
站起来  让我训练你
Rise up. Let me train you.
-训练我  -快反抗
- Train me? - Fight it, all right?
快反抗  我会来救你的
Fight it! I'll save you.
闪电侠  闪电侠
Flash, Flash!
你必须处理痛苦
You have to deal with the pain!
不
No!
你逃不开你的内心
Can't get away from what's inside you,
所以别逃了
so stop trying!
闪电侠
Flash!
9000拉德
9,000 rads.
7008拉德
马上就要爆炸了
The whole place is gonna blow.
闪电侠
Flash!
那不是你的错
Wasn't your fault!
拉尔夫  我会救你的
Ralph, I'll save you!
你已经救了我  巴里
You already did, Barry.
他就要暴发了
He's burning up!
该给你降降温了
Time to get cold-blooded.
8000拉德
8,000 rads.
辐射信号  8058拉德
辐射信号  7046拉德
7000拉德
7,000 rads.
继续用冰冻枪喷他  有效果
Keep icing him, it's working.
还在下降
And dropping.
他已被控制
He's contained.
他们成功了
They did it.
闪电侠在哪里
Where's The Flash?
巴里  怎么了  巴里
Barry. What's going on, Barry?
他信任我  乔
He trusted me, Joe.
我让他失望了
I let him down.
拉尔夫
Ralph,
他是因为我才死的
I'm the reason he's dead.
-不是  -就是
- No. - No.
-不是  -我辜负了他  我...
- No. - I failed him, I...
我该为他负责的
He was my responsibility.
现在他走了
Now he's gone.
没事的
It's all right.
我们能确保辐射被控制住了吗
So we're sure that Fallout is secure?
莱拉说她有些人
Well, Lyla said she had some people
对帮助博尔曼控制他的能力
who would be very interested
非常感兴趣
in helping Borman control his powers.
她把他带去了另一个天眼会的秘密行动队
She took him to a different A.R.G.U.S. Black-ops site
-远离一切监控  -有多远离
- way off the grid. - How far off the grid?
远到  杰克·莱恩得花上
Like, it would take Jack Ryan
汤姆·克兰西《猎杀红色十月》等一系列小说的主角
两部汤姆·克兰西小说才能找到
two Tom Clancy novels to find him.
我得说  不管在哪个地球
I got to say, on any Earth,
史纳特都风姿出众  非常合身
Snarts have style. Perfect fit.
就知道你有办法穿出彩来
Thought you could do something with it.
-你穿着很好看  -谢谢
- You wear it well. - Thank you.
你们真的不能来参加婚礼吗
You sure you can't come to the wedding?
我能安排你们
I could put all of you
都和雷的叔叔斯基普坐一桌
at a table with Ray's uncle Skip.
他杀了玛卡雷娜
He murders the Macarena.
迪沃还逍遥法外呢
Yeah, DeVoe's still out there.
随你们便吧
Suit yourselves.
但如果你想找个地方度蜜月
But if you're looking for a place to honeymoon,
我们的地球有几处美不胜收的地方
our Earth has some pretty spectacular spots.
这是什么
What is this?
那是一个跨纬度的外推器
That is an inter-dimensional extrapolator.
能产生小尺度的缺口
It makes small-scale breaches.
以防万一  雷的叔叔斯基普
You know, in case Ray's uncle Skip
想看看另一半是怎么生活的
wants to see how the other half lives.
真是厉害
Oh, well, look at that.
一点新  一点旧
Something old, something new,
一点借来的  一点蓝
something borrowed, something navy.
我们会想你的  莱昂
We're gonna miss you, Leo.
我也会想你的  凯特琳
Gonna miss you, too, Caitlyn.
你可真是不简单
You're quite the badass, you know.
足够让另一个你骄傲了
Enough to make your alter-ego proud.
谢谢
Thank you.
韦斯特警探
Detective West,
我知道地球一上的我
I know my Earth-1 counterpart
没少给你找麻烦
gave you a lot of headaches.
希望我能弥补一二
Hopefully I've begun to make up for that.
兄弟  你阻止了核弹炸平这座城市
Man, you prevented a nuke from leveling the city.
我们两清了
We're good.
西斯科  我会想念你头发的
Cisco, I'm really gonna miss that hair.
好吧
Okay.
爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦
Iris West-Allen,
谢谢你帮我
thank you for helping me
再一次打倒了那个纳粹人渣
take down Nazi scum, again.
再说一次  不客气
You're welcome, again.
然后还有一个人
And then there was one.
我明白为什么另一个史纳特
I could see why the other Snart
重新开始  加入了好人的一方
turned over a new leaf and joined the good guys.
你对身边的所有人都非常友善
You treat everyone around you with kindness
非常尊敬
and respect.
要记得也要这样对待自己
Just remember to do the same for yourself,
时不时的对自己好一点
every once in a while.
谢谢你帮我度过悲伤
Thanks for helping me push through.
小意思  巴里
Anytime, Barry.
不要变成陌生人
Don't be a stranger.
世事难料
Oh, you never know.
你还好吗
How you doing?
我知道昨晚很难熬
I know last night was pretty rough.
等我们见了分克医生再说
I'll tell you about it when we see Dr. Finkle.
我们要见分克医生吗
We're seeing Dr. Finkle?
是的  我已经预约了
Yeah, I gave her a call.
你还好吗
How's it going?
我也不知道
I don't know.
带着核超能力者一路奔波
Hauling a nuclear meta across the state,
被尖啸的疯子挟持
getting kidnapped by a screeching psychopath,
又拯救了这座城市
and helping to save the city.
要我说对于一个没有
I'd say that's pretty impressive
一半超能力者支持的人来说  挺厉害的
for someone without a meta other half to lean on.
谢谢
Thanks.
昨天我才发现
You know, the thing I realized yesterday
即使我可以过没有冰霜杀手的生活
is even though I can live without Killer Frost,
我也不想那么做
I don't think I want to.
再测试几次看看
Run some more tests, find out for sure.
-已经测过了  -结果呢
- I already did. - And?
我还不敢看
I've been too afraid to find out.
那我们就一起看
Let's find out together.
这是什么意思
What does it say?
这个意思是  我的身体之所以
It says the reason dark matter
不能吸收暗物质的原因是因为没有暗物质
isn't registering in my body is because there is none.
所以她是消失了吗
So she's gone?
这里显示还有另外一股低温异常
It says there's still another cryogenic anomaly
存在于我的DNA中
in my DNA.
冰霜杀手还在你体内
Killer Frost is still a part of you.
我只需要找出让她显现的办法
I just have to figure out how to get her to appear.
你要出门吗
You going somewhere?
是的  我要趁着意识还清醒
Yeah, matter of fact I'm gonna go visit my daughter
去见见我女儿
while I'm still of somewhat sound mind.
反正我留在这里也帮不了你们
It's not like I can help you guys around here anyway.
因为这是你残存的记忆中
Cause that is the only part of you that matters,
-唯一关心的事  -没错
- that mind of yours. - Exactly.
所以杰西才会这么优秀吗
Is that why Jesse turned out so great?
或许吧  我也不知道
Yep. No, I don't know.
你究竟想说什么
What's your point?
杰西·快客  超级英雄  科学家...
Jesse Quick, superhero, scientist...
这些我都知道
Yeah, I know who she is.
完美得无可挑剔
All around wonderful person,
她这么优秀是因为...
she turned out that way because...
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得你知道
I think you do.
你跟我说你就要失去
You told me you were about to lose
唯一有价值的东西了
the only part of you that has value.
是的  没错
Yeah. Yeah.
抚养出杰西吗
Raising Jesse?
抚养出一个如此优秀的孩子
Raising a kid that turns out like that.
需要的不仅仅是智慧
That takes a lot more than intelligence.
如果你去问她  我可以肯定她会告诉你
If you asked her, I'm pretty sure she'd tell you
五岁就能跟着数学痴父亲
learning quadratic equations at age five
学解二次方程
from her math-obsessed father
远远没有父亲对她的守护
wasn't nearly as important to her as having a dad
和关爱重要
who was there for her and who gave a damn.
所以我想说的是...
So, my point is...
说得好
Well-taken.
所以现在怎么做
So now what?
坐下来等我变成一个傻子吗
Sit around and wait until I regress to a simpleton?
现在我们来寻找治愈你的方法
Now we figure out a way to fix you.
就像巴里失去神速力时你所做的
Just like you did when Barry lost his speed.
我们要想办法...
We find a way to...
重启你的大脑
jump start your brain.
但难就难在
But this is the hard part,
这需要我们所有人通力合作
'cause it's gonna take all of us to do it,
所以...  你必须向大家坦白
which means... you have to tell the team.
我会告诉大家
I gotta tell the team.
我知道你说得没错  但是...
Yeah, I know you're right, but...
今天不行
maybe not today.
随时都可以
When you're ready.
-拉蒙  -怎么
- Ramon. - Yeah?
谢谢
Thank you.
我认识拉尔夫是在...
I knew Ralph since...
我刚获得神速力的时候
I was a rookie on the force.
一直以来我都自认为
And all that time, I thought I knew
很了解他
exactly what kind of person he was.
为什么这么觉得
Why is that?
我们的意见从来没有一致过
We just never saw things the same way, you know?
我一直都被教导人性本善
I was raised to believe that people are good.
拉尔夫呢
And Ralph?
他总是能看到人性罪恶的一面
He always saw the worst in people,
并且知道如何利用这一点
and he knew how to take advantage of it.
但是  他变了
But, um...he changed.
没错  他变了...
He did. He changed, and...
但是很长一段时间
I couldn't see that
我都没意识到这一点
for a long time.
现在我终于能...
And now that I can...
这就我最难过的地方
I think that's what's so hard is,
我很想念拉尔夫
you know, of course, I miss Ralph,
但我用了那么久
but it just took me so long
才意识到他的改变
to see what he'd become.
我甚至没有机会告诉他
I just never had a chance to tell him
作为他的朋友
just how proud I am
我有多骄傲
to be his friend.
我会一直骄傲下去
And I always will be.
我相信他知道的  巴里
I'm sure he knew that, Barry.
是的
Yeah.
如果他还能回来
What else would you tell him,
你想对他说什么
if you could right now?
我很抱歉
That I feel responsible.
我为发生的一切道歉
I feel responsible for what happened.
他教会了我  我所不能的
And he taught me more than I could have ever taught him.
为此  我会永远心怀感激
And for that, I'll always be grateful.
一切都自然而然地
Allowing events to unfold naturally
向我们倾斜
turned out in our favor.
就像你预言的那样
Just as you said it would.
而我们的胜利
And success came our way without the hindrance
也没有受到人类愚蠢情感的...
of that most aberrant of human follies...
阻碍
Emotion.
确实如此
It did, indeed.
曾有一刻
And to think, for a moment there,
我不仅想到
I experienced doubt.
或许现在你可以相信
So perhaps now you can accept
背弃艾伦先生
that the primitive cognitive entanglements
那原始的意识的纷乱
that derailed Mr. Allen today
只是为了阻止我们
can only serve to hold us back
达成我们今天的成就
from completing our work.
没错
Yes.
现在我懂了
I see that now.
比以前懂得更透彻了
More clear than ever before.